A Guide to the Rockefeller family Associates, Berent Friele papers FA468
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Business, Corporate, and Political Files, 4; 4.27 Cubic Feet 10 letter document boxes and 1 legal document box
  - Summary of Findings and Recommendations of IBEC, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 237)
    A report on a study of the International Basic Economy Corporation undertaken by McKinsey & Company for the president of IBEC, Nelson A. Rockefeller. Includes recommendations on how to improve efficiency and profitability in the organization as well as facts and figures.
  - United States Council, 1951-1952 (Box 17, Folder 238)
    Contains documents and correspondence relating to the US Council of the International Chamber of Commerce dealing in particular with trade barriers and free exchange of goods between countries. Contains pamphlets on trade barriers and red tape as well as proposals to end them. Also contains a memorandum titled "A Study of Conditions Affecting Foreign Direct Investment" which outlines factors in effective investment in Brazil.
  - United States Council, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 239)
    Contains more documents related to the US Council of the International Chamber of Commerce including meeting minutes and another copy of the memorandum included in the previous folder. Includes newspaper and magazine articles on the subject.
  - United States Machinery Company, 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 240)
    Contains correspondence and business documents pertaining to the US Machinery Co. and its activities in Brazil.
  - US-Brazil Bi-National Conference, 1970-1979 (Box 18, Folder 241)
    Continued correspondence by Friele and David Rockefeller concerning tightening of relations between US and Brazil. Also includes short biography of David Rockefeller highlighting his achievements as Chairman of Chase Manhattan Bank, specifically those related to the company's affairs in Latin America.
  - US-Brazil Relations, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 242)
    Numerous reports, statistics, and letters concerning the state of US-Brazilian relations, mostly compiled by the Commission on United States-Brazilian Relations, as well as reports on the economy of Brazil. Contains newspaper clippings.
  - US-Latin American Relations, 1969-1970 (Box 18, Folder 243)
    A packet which contains information relating the historical relationship between the United States and the Latin American countries as well as contemporary information and future plans for that relationship.
  - Various Company Correspondence, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 244)
    Contains correspondence between Berent Friele and associates relating to a variety of companies with which Friele is either conducting business or a part of. Contains a short biography/resume of Berent Friele as well as one Marshall Saunders. Includes newspaper clippings.
  - Various Press, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 245)
    Further assortment of press articles on the subject of current events and affairs in Latin America. Includes newspaper clippings.
  - Venezuela Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 18, Folder 246)
    Includes letters to and from both Nelson Rockefeller and Berent Friele. Notably includes letter written from Nelson to then President of Venezuela Carlos A. Perez. Also includes several letters expressing sorrow for the loss of several associates of Nelson and Friele. Details included about a new Caracas-Brasilia dialogue concerning trade between the two states.
  - Vice President Aureliano Chaves Visit, 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 247)
    Contains details, itineraries, and schedules relating to the visit of Brazilian politician Aureliano Chaves to the United States and their relation to Nelson Rockefeller. Contains a note relating to a meeting between Chaves, Nelson Rockefeller, and David Rockefeller.
- Photographs, 5; 0.85 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box and 1 legal document box
  - Brazilian City Photographs, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 248)
    Photographs of cityscapes from a Brazilian city, gifted to Nelson Rockefeller.
  - Photographs, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 249)
    Photo album of various events and people relating to the Rockefeller family, primarily focusing on Brazil and its fishing industry. Contains a letter from Nelson Rockefeller to an associate regarding the International Basic Economy Corporation.
  - Steven C. Rockefeller Wedding Photos, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 250)
    Restricted from access.